美国精神病人
今晚的面点是柠檬草汁鱿鱼方饺
Our pasta this evening is squid ravioli in a lemon grass broth
配上山羊奶酪泡芙
with goat cheese profiteroles,
还有芝麻菜凯撒沙拉
and I also have an arugula Caesar salad.
今晚的主菜
For entrees this evening,
有剑鱼肉卷配洋葱酱
I have swordfish meatloaf with onion marmalade,
桑梅汁嫩烤松鸡胸肉
rare-roasted partridge breast
配上酢浆草烤馅饼
in raspberry coulis with a sorrel timbale.
还有烤野兔配香草炸薯条
And grilled free-range rabbit with herbed french fries.
今晚的面点是柠檬草汁鱿鱼方饺
Our pasta tonight is a squid ravioli in a lemon grass broth,
今晚的鱼是烘烤...
and the fish tonight is grilled...
还有一杯双倍意式浓缩咖啡
With a double espresso.
天哪  我恨这个地方  这是娘们来的餐厅
God, I hate this place. It's a chicks' restaurant.
我们为什么不去多西亚餐厅
Why aren't we at Dorsia?
因为贝特曼不肯给那个领班口交
Because Bateman won't give the matre d' head.
那是里德·罗宾逊吗
Is that Reed Robinson over there?
你嗑嗨了吗  那不是罗宾逊
Are you freebasing or what? That's not Robinson.
-那么那家伙是谁  -保罗·艾伦
- Well, who is it, then? - lt's Paul Allen.
那不是保罗·艾伦
That's not Paul Allen.
保罗·艾伦在餐厅的另一边
Paul Allen's on the other side of the room over there.
-他的女伴是谁  -皮博迪公司的某只狐狸精吧
- Who's he with? - Some weasel from Kicker Peabody.
这里的洗手间可真不适合用来吸粉
They don't have a good bathroom to do coke in.
你确定那是保罗·艾伦吗
Are you sure that's Paul Allen over there?
是的  蠢货  我很确定
Yes, McDoofus, I am.
他在负责费舍那个客户
He's handling the Fisher account.
走运的混蛋
Lucky bastard.
走运的犹太混蛋
Lucky Jew bastard.
天哪  麦克德莫特  这和犹太裔有什么关系
Jesus, McDermott, what does that have to do with anything?
我见过那个混蛋坐在自己办公室里
I've seen that bastard sitting in his office
一边和首席执行官打电话  一边转犹太烛台玩
talking on the phone to the CEO, spinning a fuckin' menorah.
不是犹太烛台  是犹太陀螺
Not a menorah. You spin a dreidel.
天哪  贝特曼
Oh, my God, Bateman,
需要我给你做点土豆煎饼吗
you want me to fry you up some fuckin' potato pancakes?
土豆煎饼是犹太光明节的传统食物
-马铃薯饼  -不用了  你就
- Some latkes? - No, just
别再发表反犹太的言论了
cool it with the anti-Semitic remarks.
我忘了  贝特曼在和公民自由协会的姑娘约会
I'd forgotten. Bateman's dating someone from the ACLU.
他就是理性之声  邻家男孩
He's the voice of reason. The boy next door.
说到理性
Speaking of reasonable...
只要五百七
Only $570.
还行
Not bad.
-充实一下钱包  -把五十给她
- A little something for the purse. - Give her the $50.
两杯苏连红  加冰
Two Stoli on the rocks.
这些不能用了
These aren't good anymore.
酒吧只收现金
It's a cash bar.
一共25块
That'll be $25.
你就是个丑逼
You're a fucking ugly bitch.
我想捅死你
I want to stab you to death,
再玩玩你的血
then play around with your blood.
二位要什么
What can I get for you two?
我住在西81街上
I live in the American Gardens building
美国花园大厦11楼
on West 81st Street, on the 11th floor.
我名叫帕特里克·贝特曼
My name is Patrick Bateman.
我今年27岁
I'm 27 years old.
我深信照料自己
I believe in taking care of myself,
规律饮食
in a balanced diet,
以及严格的锻炼计划
in a rigorous exercise routine.
清晨  如果我的脸有些浮肿
In the morning, if my face is a little puffy,
我会戴上冰眼罩  同时做卷腹
I'll put on an ice pack while doing my stomach crunches.
我现在能做一千个
I can do 1,000 now.
摘下冰袋后
After I remove the ice pack,
我会用深层清洁毛孔的洁面乳
I use a deep pore cleanser lotion.
洗澡的时候  我会用水活洁面啫喱
In the shower, I use a water-activated gel cleanser...
然后用蜂蜜杏仁身体磨砂膏
then a honey-almond body scrub,
面部则用去角质凝胶磨砂膏
and on the face, an exfoliating gel scrub.
接着我会涂上草本薄荷面膜
Then I apply an herb mint facial mask,
敷上十分钟
which I leave on for ten minutes
同时准备剩余的日常步骤
while I prepare the rest of my routine.
我一直使用不含酒精
I always use an aftershave lotion
或是酒精含量很低的须后水
with little or no alcohol,
因为酒精会使面部肌肤干燥
because alcohol dries your face out
让你看起来更老
and makes you look older.
然后是保湿霜
Then moisturizer,
还有抗衰老眼霜
then an anti-aging eye balm,
最后才是保湿防护乳液
followed by a final moisturizing protective lotion.
关于帕特里克·贝特曼  存在着一个构想
There is an idea of a Patrick Bateman.
某种抽象概念
Some kind of abstraction.
但真实的我并不存在
But there is no real me,
存在的仅仅是一具实体  让人产生错觉
only an entity, something illusory,
虽然我能藏起冰冷的目光
and though I can hide my cold gaze
并且在我们握手时  你能感受到紧握的手
and you can shake my hand and feel flesh gripping yours,
或许你甚至可以感觉到
and maybe you can even sense our lifestyles
我们的生活方式大同小异
are probably comparable,
但我并不在那里
I simply am not there.
早上好  汉密尔顿  皮肤晒得不错
Morning, Hamilton. Nice tan.
去上有氧运动课了  抱歉  有人找我吗
Aerobics class, sorry. Any messages?
里奇·哈里森要取消
Ricky Harrison has to cancel.
他没说要取消什么  也没说原因
He didn't say what he was canceling or why.
我偶尔会在哈佛俱乐部和里奇打拳击
I occasionally box with Ricky at the Harvard Club.
还有别人吗
Anyone else?
斯宾塞想和约你在17号码头的弗卢蒂酒吧喝酒
Spencer wants to meet for drinks at Flutie's, Pier 17.
-什么时候  -六点以后
- When? - After 6:00.
不行  推了
Negative. Cancel it.
我该怎么说
And what should I say?
就说不行
Just say no.
就说不行吗
Just say no?
好了  琴
Okay, Jean,
十二点半在卡莫斯餐厅订三个人的位置
I need reservations for three at Camols at 12:30,
如果不行  就换克雷恩餐厅  好吗
and if not there, try Crayons, all right?
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
等等  周四八点的时候
Wait, and I need reservations for two
在阿卡迪亚餐厅订一张双人桌
at Arcadia at 8:00 on Thursday.
是浪漫约会吗
Something romantic?
不是
No...
真笨
Silly.
算了  我自己订吧
Forget it, I'll make them.
-不  我去  -不用了
- No, I'll do it. - No, no.
听话  给我倒杯矿泉水  好吗
Be a doll and just get me a mineral water, okay?
你今天气色不错
You look nice today.
以后别穿这套衣服了
Don't wear that outfit again.
什么  我没听见
What? I didn't hear you.
我说  "以后别穿这套衣服了"
I said, "Do not wear that outfit again."
穿条连衣裙  或者短裙什么的
Wear a dress, a skirt or something.
你不喜欢这身打扮是吗
You don't like this, I take it?
别这样  你的美貌可不止于此
Come on, you're prettier than that.
多谢提醒  帕特里克
Thanks, Patrick.
就说我不在
I'm not here.
记得换高跟鞋
And high heels.
我喜欢高跟鞋
I like high heels.
鸟类朋友六百问
Feathered Friends for 600.
在求偶过程中
During courtship,
雄性军舰鸟
the male frigatebird
会鼓起红色的喉囊
inflates to enormous size the red pouch found here.
几百支  不
Hundreds. No,
上千支玫瑰
Thousands of roses,
还有很多歌帝梵牌的松露巧克力
and lots of chocolate truffles, Godiva,
还有半壳的牡蛎...
and oysters on the half shell...
我想好好听罗伯特·帕玛的新磁带
I'm trying to listen to the new Robert Palmer tape,
但伊芙琳  我所谓的未婚妻
but Evelyn, my supposed fiancée,
一直在我耳边唠叨个不停
keeps buzzing in my ear.
安妮·莱博维茨  我们要请安妮·莱博维茨
Annie Leibovitz. We'll get Annie Leibovitz.
美国著名女摄影师
还得找人录像
And we'll have to get someone to videotape.
帕特里克  我们该这么做
Patrick, we should do it.
做什么
Do what?
结婚  举办婚礼
Get married. Have a wedding.
不行  我工作太忙  抽不出时间
No, I can't take the time off work.
公司是你爸开的
Your father practically owns the company.
你可以为所欲为  笨蛋
You can do anything you like, silly.
我不想谈这事
I don't want to talk about it.
反正你也不喜欢那份工作
You hate that job anyway.
我不懂你为什么不辞职
I don't see why you just don't quit.
因为我想融入进去
Because I want to fit in.
艾斯巴斯餐厅
威廉姆斯的派对
Williams party.
当我们到达艾斯巴斯餐厅时  我都快哭了
I'm on the verge of tears by the time we arrive at Espace,
因为我很肯定我们坐不到好位置了
since I'm positive we won't have a decent table,
但我们的位置确实不错
but we do,
这让我感到一阵轻松
and relief washes over me in an awesome wave.
帕特里克  这是我表妹凡登和她男友斯塔什
Patrick, this is my cousin Vanden and her boyfriend, Stash.
他们都是艺术家
They're both artists.
-菜单是用盲文写的  -你和大家都见过面了
- The menu is in Braille. - I see you've met everyone.
你真美
You look awesome.
好吧  好吧  行了
Okay, okay, all right.
我很肯定
I'm fairly certain that
蒂莫西·布莱斯和伊芙琳在搞外遇
Timothy Bryce and Evelyn are having an affair.
蒂莫西是我认识的唯一风趣的人
Timothy is the only interesting person I know.
我几乎一点也不关心
I'm almost completely indifferent
伊芙琳是否知道我也有外遇
as to whether Evelyn knows I'm having an affair
还是和柯特妮·罗琳森  她最好的朋友
with Courtney Rawlinson, her closest friend.
柯特妮的外貌几乎无可挑剔
Courtney is almost perfect-looking.
她通常会服用一种或若干种精神类药物
She's usually operating on one or more psychiatric drugs.
今晚  我想是阿普唑仑
Tonight, I believe it's Xanax.
不过比滥用药物更让人心烦的是
More disturbing than her drug use, though,
她已经和路易斯·卡拉瑟斯订婚了
is the fact that she's engaged to Luis Carruthers,
商界最大的蠢货
the biggest doofus in the business.
告诉我  斯塔什
Tell me, Stash,
你觉不觉得苏豪区变得太过商业化了
do you think Soho is becoming too commercial?
没错  我也看到过这个问题
Yes, I read that.
谁会在乎
Who gives a rat's ass?
这也会影响到我们
Hey, that affects us.
那斯里兰卡的大屠杀呢  亲爱的
Well, what about the massacres in Sri Lanka, honey?
那也会影响我们吗
Doesn't that affect us, too?
你了解斯里兰卡吗
I mean, do you know anything about Sri Lanka?
比如锡克教徒在那里杀了数不清的以色列人
How, like, the Sikhs are killing like tons of Israelis over there?
算了  布莱斯
Come on, Bryce.
还有很多比斯里兰卡
There are a lot more important problems
更重要的问题要担心呢
than Sri Lanka to worry about.
比如
Like what?
我们必须结束种族隔离
Well, we have to end apartheid, for one,
减缓核武器军备竞赛
and slow down the nuclear arms race,
消灭恐怖主义  还有世界饥饿问题
stop terrorism, and world hunger.
我们得为无家可归的人提供食宿
We have to provide food and shelter for the homeless,
反对种族歧视
and oppose racial discrimination
促进民权
and promote civil rights,
还要促进女性平权
while also promoting equal rights for women.
我们要鼓励回归传统的道德价值观
We have to encourage a return to traditional moral values.
最重要的是
Most importantly,
我们要提倡普遍的社会关怀
we have to promote general social concern
减少年轻人的物质主义
and less materialism in young people.
帕特里克
Patrick...
你想得真周到
how thoughtful of you.
你好
Hello.
漂百  你是想说"漂白"吗
Bleach-ee? Are you trying to say "Bleaching"?
漂百  天哪  我就说两件事
Bleach-ee. Oh, my God. Two things.
首先  你不能漂白切瑞蒂的衣服  这没得说
One, you can't bleach a Cerruti. Out of the question.
衣服更干净  送您好心情
其次  我只能从圣达菲买到这些床单
Two, I can only get these sheets in Santa Fe.
这些床单很贵  我需要你们把它们洗干净
These are very expensive sheets and I really need them clean.
如果你再不闭嘴
If you don't shut your fucking mouth,
我就杀了你
I will kill you.
20分钟后  我要和罗纳德·哈里森
I have a lunch meeting at Hubert's
在休贝餐厅吃午餐
in 20 minutes with Ronald Harrison,
今天下午之前  我要你们把这些床单洗干净
and I need those sheets clean by this afternoon.
我听不懂你说的话
Listen, I cannot understand you!
太扯了  你这个蠢货
This is crazy. You're a fool.
我受不了了  你个傻逼
I can't cope with this. Stupid bitch-ee!
懂了吗
Understand?
帕特里克
Patrick?
你好  帕特里克  我就觉得是你
Hi, Patrick. I thought that was you.
你好  女士
Hello, missus.
大老远跑过来是不是有点莫名其妙
Isn't it ridiculous coming all the way up here?
但他们的确是最好的
But they really are the best.
那他们为什么不能洗掉这些污渍
Then why can't they get these stains out?
你能和他们谈谈吗
I mean, can you talk to these people or something?
我真的无法跟他们交流
I'm not getting anywhere.
那是什么污渍
What are those?
蔓越莓汁  蔓越莓苹果汁
Well, it's cranberry juice. Cranapple.
真的吗
Really?
如果你能和他们谈谈
Listen, if you could talk to them,
我真的很感激  我真的要迟到了
I would really appreciate it. I'm really late.
15分钟后我和别人在休贝餐厅约了午餐
I have a lunch appointment at Hubert's in 15 minutes.
休贝餐厅  那家搬到上城区了  是吗
Hubert's? That moved uptown, right?
天哪  听着  我得走了
Well, oh, boy, listen, I've gotta go.
多谢你了  维多利亚
Thank you, Victoria.
或许我们下周可以找时间吃顿午餐  我现在经常
Maybe we could do lunch one day next week? You know, I'm downtown
-去华尔街附近  -我不知道  维多利亚
- near Wall Street quite often now.- I don't know, Victoria.
-我一直在工作  -那周六如何
- I'm at work all the time. - What about a Saturday?
-下周六吗  -可以
- Next Saturday? - Sure.
恐怕我来不了  我买了《悲惨世界》日场的票
Can't, I'm afraid. I have a matinee of Les Mis.
听着  我真的得走了
Listen, I really got to go...
我  天哪  我会打给你的
I'll-- Christ. I'll call you.
行  你走吧
Okay. Do.
听着  你在跟路易斯约会  他人在亚利桑那州
Listen, you're dating Luis. He's in Arizona.
你在跟我上床  而我们还没做计划
You're fucking me, and we haven't made plans.
你今晚还能干点什么
What could you possibly be up to tonight?
别说了  我...
Stop it. I'm...
吃了很多锂剂吗
On a lot of lithium?
即碳酸锂  可用于治疗精神分裂症等疾病
我在等着路易斯给我打电话
Waiting for Luis to call me.
他说了他今晚会给我打电话
He said he'd call tonight.
小傻瓜...
Pumpkin...
小傻瓜  你在跟一个混蛋约会
Pumpkin, you're dating an asshole.
小傻瓜  你的约会对象是纽约最大的混蛋
Pumpkin, you're dating the biggest dickweed in New York.
小傻瓜  这家伙渣得一塌糊涂
Pumpkin, you're dating a tumbling, tumbling dickweed.
两小时超长三人行后入诱惑
帕特里克  别再叫我小傻瓜了好吗
Patrick, stop calling me pumpkin, okay?
我得挂了
I have to go.
柯特妮
Courtney!
-一起吃晚饭吧  -不行
- Dinner. - I can't!
咱们去多西亚餐厅吃吧
I'm thinking Dorsia.
多西亚挺不错的
Dorsia's nice.
穿好看点
Wear something fabulous.
多西亚餐厅
Dorsia.
是的  我知道现在有点晚了
Yes, I know it's a little late,
但有没有可能订一张八点
but is it possible to reserve a table for two
或八点半的双人桌
at 8:00 or 8:30, perhaps?
我先在伊丽莎白·雅顿做了脸部按摩  真是放松
A facial at Elizabeth Arden, which was really relaxing,
美国护肤品品牌
然后我去了陶瓷谷仓
and then to the Pottery Barn,
美国家具巨头
我在那里买了这个小小的松糕银碟
where I got this little silver muffin dish.
那是不是唐纳德·特朗普的车
Is that Donald Trump's car?
天哪  帕特里克  闭嘴吧
God, Patrick, shut up.
柯特妮  你该多吃点锂剂
You know, Courtney, you should take some more lithium
或者喝瓶健怡可乐
or have a Diet Coke.
咖啡因可以让你摆脱困倦
Some caffeine might get you out of this slump.
我只想要个孩子
I just want a child.
只要两个...
Just two...
完美的...
perfect...
孩子
children.
我们到了吗
Are we here?
是的
Yeah.
这里就是多西亚餐厅
This is Dorsia?
没错  亲爱的
Yes, dear.
柯特妮  你得喝点花生酱汤
Courtney, you're gonna have the peanut butter soup
巴卡迪亚餐厅
配上熏鸭和南瓜泥
with smoked duck and mashed squash.
《纽约日场》称其为
New York Matinee called it
"一道有趣却又神秘的小菜"
"A playful, but mysterious little dish."
你会喜欢的
You'll love it.
接着是红鲷鱼配上紫罗兰和松子
And then the red snapper with violets and pine nuts.
这两道菜一定会完美承接  相得益彰
I think that'll follow nicely.
谢谢  帕特里克
Thanks, Patrick.
帕特里克  多谢你照顾柯特妮
Patrick, thanks so much for looking after Courtney.
你居然带她去多西亚吃饭
Dorsia, how impressive.
你究竟是怎样在那里订到位置的
How on earth did you get a reservation there?
大概是走运吧
Lucky, I guess.
西装不错嘛
That's a wonderful suit.
别告诉我  别告诉我  让我猜猜
Don't tell me, don't tell me, let me guess.
华伦天奴高级定制
Valentino couture.
意大利奢侈品牌
看起来好软
It looks so soft.
你的马屁已经拍够了  路易斯
Your compliment was sufficient, Luis.
你好啊  哈博斯特拉姆  领带不错
Hello, Halberstram. Nice tie.
你最近怎么样
How the hell are ya?
艾伦把我误认成了这个傻帽马库斯·哈博斯特拉姆
Allen has mistaken me for this dickhead Marcus Halberstram.
这也挺符合逻辑的  因为马库斯也在这里工作
It seems logical because Marcus also works at P&P,
事实上  我们俩的工作内容相同
and in fact, does the same exact thing I do.
他也偏爱华伦天奴的西装
He also has a penchant for Valentino suits
和奥利弗·皮帕斯的眼镜
and Oliver Peoples glasses.
美国高端眼镜品牌
我们俩甚至连理发师都是同一个人
Marcus and I even go to the same barber,
不过我的发型要稍微好点
although I have a slightly better haircut.
所以那个要赎金的客户怎么样了  马库斯
So how's the ransom account going, Marcus?
-挺好的  -是吗
- It's all right. - Really?
真有意思  只是挺好
That's interesting. It's not,
-却没有特别棒  -你也知道的
- it's not great. - Well, you know.
塞西莉亚怎么样  她是个不错的女孩
So how's Cecilia? She's a great girl.
是啊  我很幸运
Yeah. I'm very lucky.
艾伦
Hey, Allen!
费舍那个客户恭喜你啊
Congratulations on the Fisher account.
多谢  巴克斯特
Thank you, Baxter.
保罗  打壁球吗
Listen, Paul. Squash?
到时候联系
Call me.
-周五怎么样  -不行
- How about Friday? - No can do.
我八点半在多西亚订了位置
I got an 8:30 res at Dorsia.
超美味的海胆酸橘汁腌鱼
Great sea urchin ceviche.
居然能在周五订到多西亚的位置  他怎么做到的
Dorsia on a Friday night? How'd he swing that?
我觉得他在骗人
I think he's lying.
那是张名片吗
Is that a gram?
新名片  各位觉得如何
New card. What do you think?
帕特里克·贝特曼
副总裁
挺不错
Very nice.
瞧瞧
Look at that.
昨天才从印刷店取回来的
Picked them up from the printer's yesterday.
-颜色不错  -骨白色
- Good coloring. - That's bone.
字体叫什么希里安铁轨
And the lettering is something called Silian Rail.
是挺酷  贝特曼  但那根本不算什么
It's very cool, Bateman, but that's nothing.
帕特里克·贝特曼
副总裁
大卫·范帕顿
瞧瞧这个
Look at this.
这张真的不错
That is really nice.
蛋壳白配上罗马利安字体
Eggshell with Romalian type.
你觉得如何
What do you think?
挺好
Nice.
天哪  这张真的超棒
Jesus. That is really super.
你这种笨蛋怎么会这么有品味
How did a nitwit like you get so tasteful?
真不敢相信布莱斯会更喜欢范帕顿的名片
I can't believe that Bryce prefers Van Patten 's card to mine.
不过等等
But wait.
你们还没见识到厉害
You ain't seen nothing yet.
凸出字体  雨云苍白色
Raised lettering, pale nimbus, white.
蒂莫西·布莱斯
副总裁
不错
Impressive.
非常不错
Very nice.
咱们来看看保罗·艾伦的名片吧
Let's see Paul Allen's card.
保罗·艾伦
副总裁
看看那微妙的灰白
Look at that subtle off-white coloring.
有品位的厚度
The tasteful thickness of it.
天哪
Oh, my God,
这张名片甚至有水印
it even has a watermark.
有什么问题吗  帕特里克
ls something wrong, Patrick?
你在出汗
You're sweating.
你好
Hello.
我是帕特·贝特曼  你想要钱吗
Pat Bateman. You want some money?
还是食物
Some food?
你需要这个吗
This what you need?
我很饿
I'm hungry.
是啊  你也很冷  不是吗
Yeah. Cold out, too, isn't it?
你为什么不去找份工作呢
Why don't you get a job?
如果你这么饿  为什么不去找份工作
If you're so hungry, why don't you get a job?
我丢了工作
I lost my job.
为什么  你酗酒吗
Why? You drinking?
你是因此而被解雇的吗
Is that why you lost it?
还是因为内部交易
Insider trading?
我开玩笑的
Just joking.
你叫什么名字
Listen, what's your name?
艾尔
Al.
大点声  说出来
Speak up. Come on.
-艾尔  -去他妈找份工作吧  艾尔
- Al. - Get a goddamn job, Al.
正是你消极的态度阻止了你前进
You got a negative attitude. That's what's stopping you.
你得振作起来
You gotta get your act together.
我会帮你
I'll help you.
您真善良  先生
You are so kind, mister.
您真善良  您是个好人
You're kind. You're a kind man.
-没事的  -我能看出来
- It's okay. - I can tell.
拜托  您得告诉我该怎么办
Please, you gotta tell me what to do.
您得帮帮我  我又饿又冷
You gotta help me. I'm so cold, I'm hungry.
你知道你闻起来有多臭吗
You know how bad you smell?
你臭死了  你知道吗
You reek of shit. Do you know that?
艾尔...
Al...
抱歉
I'm sorry.
只是...
It's just that...
我不知道
I don't know.
我和你毫无共同点
I don't have anything in common with you.
多谢您  先生  多谢
Thank you, mister. Thank you.
我都快被冻死了
I'm cold out here.
你知道你他妈有多失败吗
You know what a fucking loser you are?
什么
What?
您的皮肤真好  贝特曼先生
What beautiful skin you have, Mr. Bateman.
很细腻  很光滑
So fine, so smooth.
我有一个人类的所有特征
I have all the characteristics of a human being:
血  肉  皮肤  头发
flesh, blood, skin, hair,
但我却没有任何一种清晰可辨的情绪
but not a single clear identifiable emotion
除了贪婪和厌恶
except for greed and disgust.
某些可怕的事正在我的内心滋长
Something horrible is happening inside of me,
而我不知道原因
and I don't know why.
我在夜间嗜血的欲望已经蔓延到了白天
My nightly blood lust has overflowed into my days.
我觉得自己是个破坏狂  处在暴怒的边缘
I feel lethal, on the verge of frenzy.
我觉得我理智的面具就快滑落了
I think my mask of sanity is about to slip.
麦考伊  你觉得怎么样
Hey, McCoy, what do you say?
汉密尔顿  祝你度过一个快乐的圣诞节
Hey, Hamilton, have a holly, jolly Christmas.
费舍那个客户还在归艾伦管吗
Is Allen still handling the Fisher account?
当然了  不然还能归谁管
Of course. Who else?
有槲寄生哦  圣诞快乐  帕特里克
Mistletoe alert. Merry X-mas, Patrick.
西方传统  在槲寄生下必须接吻
圣诞快乐  哈利
Merry X-mas, Harry.
-圣诞快乐  -你迟到了  亲爱的
- Merry Christmas. - You're late, honey.
-我没迟到  -你就是迟到了
- No. - Yes, you are.
我一直都在  只是你没看见我罢了
I've been here the entire time, you just didn't see me.
跟雪球打个招呼
Say hello to Snowball.
雪球说  "圣诞快乐  帕特里克"
Snowball says, "Merry Christmas, Patrick."
这是什么东西
What is it?
这是一只小猪猪  是不是呀
It's a baby piggy-wiggy, isn't it?
这是只越南大肚猪
It's a Vietnamese potbellied pig.
它们是很可爱的宠物  对不对呀
They make darling pets. Don't you?
对不对呀
Don't you?
别再皱眉了  帕特里克
Stop scowling, Patrick.
你真扫兴
You're such a Grinch.
扫兴先生想要什么圣诞礼物
What does Mr. Grinch want for Christmas?
别再说是隆胸了
And don't say breast implants again.
-艾伦  -马库斯  圣诞快乐
- Allen. - Marcus! Merry Christmas.
你怎么样  一直在忙工作吧  我猜
How you been? Workaholic, I suppose?
有段时间没见了
I haven't seen you in a while.
汉密尔顿
Hey, Hamilton!
我们要去内尔餐厅了  轿车在门口等了
We're going to Nell's. Limo's out front.
我们应该吃个晚餐
We should have dinner.
也许你可以带上...
Maybe you could bring...
-塞西莉亚  -没错  塞西莉亚
- Cecilia? - Yes, Cecilia!
塞西莉亚会喜欢的
Cecilia would adore it.
那就这么定了  马库斯
Well, then let's do it, Marcus.
-派对不错  -多谢夸奖
- Great party. - Thanks.
帕特里克  为什么他叫你马库斯
Patrick, why is he calling you Marcus?
有槲寄生哦
Mistletoe alert.
马库斯·哈博斯特拉姆在七点订的双人桌
Marcus Halberstram for two at 7:00.
不  我想知道
No, I want to know.
我来是为了香菜小龙虾秋葵汤  好吗
Okay, I came here for the cilantro crawfish gumbo, all right?
毕竟  来这家门可罗雀的餐厅的人
which is, after all, the only excuse one could have for being
也只能是
in this restaurant which is,
为了吃这道菜
by the way, almost completely empty.
非常抱歉  先生
I'm very sorry, sir.
珍宝威士忌  不加冰  再来一瓶科罗娜啤酒
J&B straight, and a Corona.
二位想不想听听
Would you like to hear--
双份用绝对伏特加调的马提尼
Double Absolut martini.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
二位想听听本餐厅的特色菜吗
Would you like to hear the specials?
如果你还想要你的脾脏  那就闭嘴
Not if you want to keep your spleen.
这儿真热闹  哈博斯特拉姆
This is a real beehive of activity, Halberstram.
这个地方很火  特别火
This place is hot. Very hot.
听我说  这里的黑豆汤
Listen, the mud soup
和炭烧芝麻菜非常不错
and charcoal arugula are outrageous here.
好吧  你迟到了
Yeah, well, you're late.
我是单亲家庭的孩子  饶了我吧
Hey, I'm a child of divorce. Give me a break.
我发现他们删掉了猪排配青柠果冻
I see they've omitted the pork loin with lime Jell-O.
我们应该去多西亚
We should've gone to Dorsia.
我可以给咱俩订到座位
I could have gotten us a table.
没有人再去那里了
Nobody goes there anymore.
那个是伊凡娜·特朗普吗
Is that Ivana Trump?
天哪  帕特里克
Jeez, Patrick--
我是说  马库斯
I mean, Marcus...
你在想什么啊
What are you thinking?
伊凡娜怎么会在特克萨卡纳餐厅呢
Why would lvana be at Texarkana?
话说...
So...
之前负责费舍的不是罗斯柴尔德吗
Wasn't Rothschild originally handling the Fisher account?
怎么会到你手上
How'd you get it?
我可以告诉你事情原委  哈博斯特拉姆
Well, I could tell you that, Halberstram,
但那样的话我就得杀了你
but then I'd have to kill you.
我喜欢解剖女孩
I like to dissect girls.
你知道我完全疯了吗
Did you know I'm utterly insane?
肤色晒得不错  马库斯  非常棒
Great tan, Marcus. I mean, really impressive.
-你在哪里晒的  -沙龙
- Where do you tan? - Salon.
我家里有一台日晒床  你应该试试
I've got a tanning bed at home. You should look into it.
那个...
And...
塞西莉亚  她怎么样
Cecilia... how is she?
她今晚去哪了
Where is she tonight?
塞西莉亚去...
Cecilia is...
她这人你也知道
Well, you know Cecilia.
我想她今天的晚餐是和...
I think she's having dinner with...
伊芙琳·威廉姆斯一起吃的
Evelyn Williams.
伊芙琳
Evelyn.
她屁股不错
Great ass.
和那个废物帕特里克·贝特曼在一起
Goes out with that loser Patrick Bateman.
他真是个呆子
What a dork.
要再来杯马提尼吗  保罗
Another martini, Paul?
休易·路易斯和新闻乐队[美国摇滚乐队]
《瞩目》
你喜欢休易·路易斯和新闻乐队吗
You like Huey Lewis and the News?
他们还行吧
They're okay.
他们的早期作品对我来说有点太新浪潮了
Their early work was a little too new wave for my taste.
但当83年《运动》问世时
But when Sports came out in '83,
我觉得他们才真正找到自己的特色  崭露头角
I think they really came into their own,
商业上和艺术上都是
commercially and artistically.
整张专辑听起来清脆悦耳
The whole album has a clear, crisp sound,
精湛的专业水平带来的熠熠光辉
and a new sheen of consummate professionalism
让他们的歌曲有了质的飞跃
that really gives the songs a big boost.
纽约药房
帕特里克·贝特曼
服药请遵医嘱
他一直被人拿来和埃尔维斯·科斯特洛比较
He's been compared to Elvis Costello,
英国流行摇滚歌手
但我觉得休易具有更加激烈的
but I think Huey has a far more bitter,
愤世嫉俗的幽默感
cynical sense of humor.
-哈博斯特拉姆  -怎么了  艾伦
- Hey, Halberstram. - Yes, Allen?
为什么这里到处都是报纸的时尚版
Why are there copies of the Style section all over the place?
你是...  你是养了狗吗
Do you-- Do you have a dog?
小松狮犬之类的吗
A little chow or something?
不  艾伦
No, Allen.
那是雨衣吗
Is that a raincoat?
是的
Yes, it is.
87年  休易发行了这张专辑
In '87, Huey released this,
《瞩目》  他们最成功的一张专辑
Fore!, their most accomplished album.
我觉得他们的《循规蹈矩也很酷》
I think their undisputed masterpiece is
是无可辩驳的杰作
"Hip To Be Square".
这首歌特别琅琅上口
The song's so catchy.
大多数人可能都不会去听歌词
Most people probably don't listen to the lyrics.
但是他们应该听一听
But they should,
因为这首歌不只唱出了循规蹈矩的愉悦
because it's not just about the pleasures of conformity
和随大流的重要性
and the importance of trends.
乐队自身也借这首歌抒发了自我
It's also a personal statement about the band itself.
保罗
Hey, Paul!
现在再去多西亚订座啊
Try getting a reservation at Dorsia now,
你这个愚蠢的混蛋
you fucking stupid bastard!
你这个该死的混蛋
You fucking bastard!
他当时完全赤裸  站在桌子上
He was completely naked and he was standing on the table,
身无片缕...
with no clothes on--
帕特里克  帕特里克
Patrick? Patrick!
是你吗
Is that you?
不  路易斯  不是我  你搞错了
No, Luis, it's not me. You're mistaken.
这是我非常好的朋友  帕特里克·贝特曼
This is my very good friend, Patrick Bateman.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
我们要去内尔餐厅
We're going to Nell's.
格温多琳的父亲请客
Gwendolyn's father is buying it.
那个旅行袋你在哪买的
Where did you get that overnight bag?
让·保罗·高缇耶
Jean Paul Gaultier.
法国设计师品牌
当我到达保罗·艾伦的住处时
When I get to Paul Allen's place,
我用从他口袋里拿的钥匙开了门
I use the keys I took from his pocket
钥匙是在处理尸体前拿的
before disposing of the body.
我一度感到十分恐慌
There is a moment of sheer panic
当我意识到他的公寓能俯瞰中央公园
when I realize that Paul's apartment overlooks the park
并且显然比我的公寓更贵时
and it's obviously more expensive than mine.
我让自己冷静下来  走进了卧室
I calm myself and move into the bedroom,
我在那里找到了他的行李箱  开始收拾
where I find his suitcase and start to pack.
保罗是时候出去转一转了
It's time for Paul to take a little trip.
要送这个混蛋去哪呢
Where to send the bastard?
达拉斯
Dallas?
巴黎  新加坡
Paris? Singapore?
伦敦  我要送这混蛋去伦敦
London. I'll send the ass to London.
你好  我是保罗
Hi, this is Paul.
我最近受召要去伦敦几天
I've been called away to London for a few days.
梅瑞迪丝  等我回来再打给你
Meredith, I'll call you when I get back.
后会有期  宝贝
Hasta la vista, baby.
怎么了
What is it?
帕特里克
Patrick?
怎么了  琴
Yes, Jean?
有一位唐纳德·坎鲍尔先生要见你
There's a Mr. Donald Kimball here to see you.
谁
Who?
唐纳德·坎鲍尔侦探
Detective Donald Kimball.
告诉他我去吃午饭了
Tell him I'm at lunch.
帕特里克  现在才十点半
Patrick, it's only 10:30.
我想他知道你在这里
I think he knows you're here.
那就让他进来吧
Send him in, I guess.
约翰
Now, John,
你得穿和你身材相称的衣服
you've gotta wear clothes in proportion to your physique.
哥们儿  穿粗条纹衬衫时
There are definite dos and don'ts, good buddy,
绝对应该注意搭配的技巧和禁忌
of wearing a bold-striped shirt.
粗条纹衬衫要配纯色
A bold-striped shirt calls for solid-colored
或者暗纹的西装和领带
or discreetly patterned suits and ties.
是的  一定要给造型师15%的小费
Yes, always tip the stylist 15%.
约翰  我得挂了
Listen, John, I've got to go.
T·布恩·皮肯斯刚走了进来
T. Boone Pickens just walked in.
美国著名金融家
开玩笑啦
Just joking.
不  不要给沙龙店老板小费
No, don't tip the owner of the salon.
好吗  约翰  对
Okay, John? Right.
明白
Got it.
抱歉
Sorry about that.
不  该抱歉的是我  我应该先预约的
No, I'm sorry. I should've made an appointment.
刚刚是什么重要的事吗
Was that anything important?
刚刚那通电话吗  只是在考虑生意上的问题
That? Just mulling over business problems,
考察机会  交换传闻
examining opportunities, exchanging rumors,
传播八卦
spreading gossip.
你好  我是唐纳德·坎鲍尔
Hi. I'm Donald Kimball.
你好  我是帕特·贝特曼  幸会
Hi, Pat Bateman. Nice to meet you.
抱歉我唐突了
Sorry to barge in on you like this.
我知道你们都是大忙人
I know how busy you guys can get.
所以  有什么事...
So, what's the...
要讨论呢
topic of discussion?
我受梅瑞迪丝·鲍威尔所雇
I've been hired by Meredith Powell
来调查保罗·艾伦失踪一事
to investigate the disappearance of Paul Allen.
我明白了
I see.
保罗失踪了
Paul's disappearance, yeah.
所以没什么特别正式的
So it's nothing that official.
我只要问几个简单的问题
I just have some basic questions
关于保罗·艾伦  关于你
about Paul Allen, about yourself--
-喝咖啡吗  -不用  没关系
- Coffee? - No, I'm okay.
-阿波利水  -不用  没关系
- Apollinaris? - No, I'm okay.
德国高级矿泉水品牌
你能给...
Can you bring Mr...
-坎鲍尔  -坎鲍尔先生一瓶阿波利...
- Kimball. - Mr. Kimball a bottle of Apollin--
-真的不用  没关系  -不用客气
- No, really, I'm okay. - lt's no problem.
所以有什么事要讨论呢
So, what's the topic of discussion?
保罗·艾伦的失踪
The disappearance of Paul Allen.
对
Right.
我还没有...
Well, I-- haven't--
我还没有听说任何有关失踪的事
I haven't heard anything about the disappearance or anything,
至少在杂志八卦版上没有
not on Page Six, at least.
我想他的家人希望此事保密
I think his family wants this kept quiet.
可以理解  要青柠吗
Understandable. Lime?
不用  真的没关系
No, no, really, I'm okay.
你确定吗  我完全可以给你来片青柠
You sure? I can always get you a lime.
我只想初步问几个问题
Just some preliminary questions
出于我的调查需要  好吗
that I need for my own files, okay?
问吧
Shoot.
-你今年多大  -27岁
- How old are you? - Twenty-seven.
你在哪里上的学
Where did you go to school?
哈佛  然后是哈佛商学院
Harvard, then Harvard Business School.
你的地址是
Your address?
美国花园大楼  西81街
The American Gardens building, West 81st Street.
不错  相当不错
Nice. Very nice.
谢谢
Thanks.
关于保罗·艾伦  你有什么能告诉我的
What can you tell me about Paul Allen?
我也不知道
I'm at a loss.
他是那种耶鲁风的
He was part of that whole Yale thing.
-"耶鲁风"  -是的  耶鲁风
- "Yale thing"? - Yeah, Yale thing.
你说的"耶鲁风"是什么意思
What do you mean, "Yale thing"?
比如  我觉得他大概是个没出柜的同性恋
Well, I think for one that he was probably a closet homosexual
经常吸可卡因
who did a lot of cocaine.
那种"耶鲁风"
That "Yale thing".
他是什么样的人
What kind of man was he?
除了你刚刚给我的那些信息以外
Besides the information you've just given me.
希望我现在不是在被盘问
I hope I'm not being cross-examined here.
你感觉像吗
Do you feel like that?
不  其实不太像
No, not really.
保罗经常在哪些地方活动
Where did Paul hang out?
-活动  -是的  常活动的地方
- Hang out? - Yeah, you know, hang out.
让我想想
Let me think.
纽波特餐厅  哈利酒吧
The Newport, Harry's,
弗卢蒂酒吧  中南半岛餐厅
Flutie's, Indochine,
内尔餐厅  康奈尔俱乐部
Nell's, the Cornell Club,
纽约游艇俱乐部
the New York Yacht Club.
他有游艇吗
He had a yacht?
不  他只是去那里玩
No, he just hung out there.
他在哪上的学
And where did he go to school?
这个你不知道吗
Don't you know this?
我只想知道你是否知道
I just wanted to know if you know.
在耶鲁之前  如果我没记错
Before Yale, if I remember correctly,
是圣保罗中学
Saint Paul's.
听着  我只是...
Listen, I just...
我只是想帮忙
I just want to help.
我理解
I understand.
你有发现任何目击证人或指纹吗
Do you have any witnesses or fingerprints?
在他的答录机上有一条留言
Well, there's a message on his answering machine
说他去伦敦了
that says he went to London.
也许他真去了呢
Maybe he did, huh?
他的女朋友不这么认为
His girlfriend doesn't think so.
但有人在伦敦见过他吗
But has anyone seen him in London?
事实上  有
Actually, yes,
但我在试图核实时遇到了困难
but I've had a hard time getting actual verification.
有一个叫斯蒂芬·休斯的人
A Stephen Hughes
说他在那里的一家餐厅里见过他
said he saw him at a restaurant there.
但我调查后发现  实际上
But I checked it out, and what happened is
他误把一个叫赫伯特·安斯沃思的人
he mistook a Herbert Ainsworth
当成了保罗  所以...
for Paul, so...
他的公寓被盗了吗
Had his apartment been burglarized?
不  事实上并没有
No, actually, it hadn't.
一些洗漱用品没了  一件西装不见了
Toiletries were missing, a suit was gone,
还丢了些行李  只有这些
so was some luggage. That's it.
凶案组还没有人
I mean, no one's dealing with
来介入调查吧
the homicide squad yet or anything, right?
还没有  正如我之前所说  我们还不确定
No, not yet. As I said, we're not sure.
基本上没有任何人目击或听见什么
Basically, no one's seen or heard anything.
太典型了  不是吗
So typical, isn't it?
就是很奇怪
It's just strange.
前一天这个人还在四处走动
One day someone's walking around,
去上班  好好地活着  然后...
going to work, alive, and then--
无影无踪
Nothing.
一个人就这样凭空消失了
People just disappear.
地球张开大口  把他们吞噬了
The Earth just opens up and swallows them.
可怕
Eerie.
真可怕
Really eerie.
不好意思  我得走了
Listen, you'll have to excuse me.
我和克利夫·哈克斯特博有个午餐会议
I have a lunch meeting with Cliff Huxtable
20分钟后在四季酒店
at the Four Seasons in 20 minutes.
四季酒店吗
The Four Seasons?
那地方在上城区  是不是离这里有点远
Isn't that a little far uptown?
难道你不会迟到吗
I mean, aren't you going to be late?
不  这附近就有一家
No, there's one down here.
-真的吗  我都不知道  -是的  那里很不错
- Really? I didn't know that. - Yes. It's very good.
听着
Listen,
如果你想起了任何事情  任何线索...
if anything else occurs to you, any information--
我一定会告诉你  我完全支持你
Absolutely. I'm 100% with you.
那就好
Great, and...
多谢你能抽出时间见我  贝特曼先生
thanks for your time, Mr. Bateman.
-再见  -再见
- Bye-bye. - Goodbye.
我没在这附近见过你
I haven't seen you around here.
你只是从没注意过罢了
You just haven't been looking.
想去我住的地方看看吗
Would you like to see my apartment?
按理说我不该去
I'm not supposed to.
你到底想不想去
Do you want to come to my apartment or not?
我不该去  但是你可以例外
I'm not supposed to, but I can make an exception.
可以刷信用卡吗
Do you take a credit card?
开玩笑
I'm joking.
快来  上车吧
Come on, get in.
我要叫个姑娘  20出头  金发
I'd like a girl, early 20s, blonde,
还得喜欢三人行  三人行
who does couples. Couples.
一定要金发  强调多少遍都不过分
And I really can't stress blonde enough.
要金发
Blonde.
我是保罗
I'm Paul.
我叫保罗·艾伦
My name's Paul Allen.
知道了吗
You got that?
你叫克里斯蒂
You're Christie.
叫你克里斯蒂时  你才能答应
You're to respond only to Christie.
清楚了吗
Is that clear?
你喝的那可是高档霞多丽
That's a very fine Chardonnay you're drinking.
我要你把下面洗干净
I want you to clean your vagina.
不
No.
从后面洗
From behind.
跪着
Get on your knees.
你的身体很诱人
You have a very nice body.
谢谢  让她上来
Thank you. Send her up.
克里斯蒂  出来擦干身子
Christie, get out and dry off,
挑件浴袍穿好
choose a robe,
除了那件毕扬
Not the Bijan,
美国顶级奢侈品牌
来客厅和我们的客人一起喝两杯
and come and meet me and our guest in the living room for drinks.
你来了  真好
You've arrived! How lovely.
大衣给我吧
Let me take your coat.
我是保罗
I'm Paul.
你能来真好
How good of you to come.
你的发色不够金吧
Not quite blonde, are you?
有点暗的金色
More dirty blonde.
我要叫你萨布丽娜
I'm gonna call you Sabrina.
我是保罗·艾伦
I'm Paul Allen.
那么
So...
你们不想知道我是做什么的吗
don't you want to know what I do?
不想
No.
不  不想
No. Not really.
好吧
Well,
我在华尔街工作
I work on Wall Street.
皮尔斯&皮尔斯公司
At Pierce & Pierce.
你们听说过吗
Have you heard of it?
你这里真不错  保罗
You have a really nice place here, Paul.
你花多少钱买的
How much did you pay for it?
这其实
Well, actually,
不关你的事  克里斯蒂
that's none of your business, Christie.
不过我可以向你保证
But I can assure you,
绝对不便宜
it certainly wasn't cheap.
不  不许吸烟  这里不行
No. No smoking. Not in here.
格朗松露酒
Varda truffle?
我不希望你们喝醉  但是
I don't want you to get drunk, but
你们不喝的话
that's a very fine Chardonnay
可就浪费了一瓶高档霞多丽
you're not drinking.
菲尔·柯林斯
你们喜欢听菲尔·柯林斯吗
Do you like Phil Collins?
英国歌手  在创世纪乐队中担任主唱兼鼓手
我是创世纪乐队的超级粉丝
I've been a big Genesis fan
从他们1980年发行了《杜克》那张专辑以来就是了
ever since the release of their 1980 album, Duke.
在那之前
Before that,
他们的作品我一点都听不懂
I really didn't understand any of their work.
艺术性太强  让人听不懂
It was too artsy, too intellectual.
正是《杜克》这张专辑
It was on Duke where
才让菲尔·柯林斯在乐队中的地位更加明确
Phil Collins' presence became more apparent.
我认为《无形的触碰》这张专辑
I think Invisible Touch
是乐队无可争议的杰作
is the group's undisputed masterpiece.
那是一次关于无形的
It's an epic meditation
史诗般的冥想
on intangibility.
与此同时  它深化并丰富了
At the same time, it deepens and enriches
前三张专辑的意蕴
the meaning of the preceding three albums.
克里斯蒂
Christie,
脱掉浴袍
take off the robe.
你听那精彩的合奏
Listen to the brilliant ensemble playing
班克斯的键盘  柯林斯的鼓  和路德佛的吉他
of Banks, Collins, and Rutherford.
你能听到每种乐器的细微差别
You can practically hear every nuance of every instrument.
萨布丽娜  把裙子脱了
Sabrina, remove your dress.
在写词的技艺
In terms of lyrical craftsmanship,
和纯粹的歌曲创作方面
sheer songwriting,
这张专辑达到了专业水准的新巅峰
this album hits a new peak of professionalism.
萨布丽娜  不如你稍微跳跳舞吧
Sabrina, why don't you dance a little?
比如《混沌之地》这首歌的歌词
Take the lyrics to "Land Of Confusion."
菲尔·柯林斯通过这首歌
In this song, Phil Collins addresses the problems
直击滥用政治权力的问题
of abusive political authority.
而《深陷其中》是80年代最感人的流行歌
"In Too Deep" is the most moving pop song of the 1980s,
讲的是一夫一妻制和承诺
about monogamy and commitment.
这首歌极其振奋人心
The song is extremely uplifting.
歌词的积极向上和确定感
Their lyrics are as positive and affirmative
可以与我在摇滚中听到的元素相媲美
as anything I've heard in rock.
克里斯蒂
Christie,
跪下让萨布丽娜能看到你的后庭
get down on your knees so Sabrina can see your asshole.
菲尔·柯林斯的单飞生涯
Phil Collins' solo career
似乎更商业化
seems to be more commercial,
从某种狭隘的角度来说
and therefore more satisfying
也因此更令人满意了
in a narrower way.
尤其是像《今夜无处不在》
Especially songs like "ln The Air Tonight"
和《希望渺茫》这两首歌
and "Against All Odds."
萨布丽娜  别光盯着看  用嘴
Sabrina, don't just stare at it. Eat it.
但我还是认为
But I also think
菲尔·柯林斯在乐队的表现最好
Phil Collins works best within the confines of the group
而不是单飞艺术家
than as a solo artist.
我要强调一下"艺术家"这个词
And I stress the word "artist."
这首歌是《萨苏迪欧》
This is "Sussudio."
很棒很棒的一首歌
A great, great song.
个人最爱
A personal favorite.
看着镜头
Look at the camera.
克里斯蒂  看镜头
Christie, look at the camera.
别碰手表
Don't touch the watch.
我们能走了吗
Can we go now?
还没完事呢
We're not through yet.
如果她们性格很好但长得不好看
If they have a good personality and they're not great-looking,
那谁他妈还在乎
then who fuckin' cares?
就假设一下  好吗
Just say, hypothetically, okay,
如果她们性格很好呢
what if they have a good personality?
我知道  我知道...
I know, I know...
不存在性格好的女孩子
There are no girls with good personalities.
好性格就是小妞身材紧实
A good personality consists of a chick with a little hard body
能满足你所有的性需求
who'll satisfy all sexual demands
同时还不能太浪
without being too slutty about things,
而且还能管住嘴巴不八卦
and will essentially keep her dumb fucking mouth shut.
性格好的女孩子
The only girls with good personalities
要么聪明  要么有趣
who are smart, or maybe funny,
要么智商不低  要么才华横溢
or halfway intelligent or talented,
鬼才知道我讲的是什么样的女孩
though God knows what the fuck that means,
-那一定都是丑八怪  -绝对
- are ugly chicks. - Absolutely.
这正是因为她们不得不弥补
And this is because they have to make up
自己毫无吸引力的事实
for how fucking unattractive they are.
你们知道关于女人  艾德·盖恩是怎么说吗
Do you know what Ed Gein said about women?
哪个艾德·盖恩  运河酒吧的领班吗
Ed Gein? Matre d' at Canal Bar?
不  是50年代威斯康辛州的连环杀手
No. Serial killer. Wisconsin in the '50s.
-艾德怎么说  -他说
- And what did Ed say? - He said,
"当我看到漂亮姑娘走在街上
"When I see a pretty girl walking down the street,
我有两个念头
I think two things.
一个我想要跟她约会  聊天
One part of me wants to take her out and talk to her,
用心待她  全心全意"
be real nice and sweet and treat her right."
另一个他怎么想
And what did the other part of him think?
"把棍子插进她的脑袋会是什么景象"
"What her head would look like on a stick."
伙计们
Hi, guys.
我需要你们的意见
I want to get your opinion on something.
是我的名片
It's my business card.
我也决定重新定制一款
I decided to get a new one, too.
这个...
That's...
很不错  路易斯
Very nice, Luis.
多谢夸奖
Thank you.
路易斯·卡拉瑟斯
副总裁
对了  晚饭怎么办
Listen, what about dinner?
你能说的就这些吗  范帕顿
Is that all you ever have to contribute, Van Patten?
"见鬼的晚饭怎么办"
"What about fucking dinner?"
别丧气  贝特曼
Cheer up there, Bateman.
怎么了  今早忘记做按摩了吗
What's the matter, no shiatsu this mornin'?
再碰我一下  我要你好看
Touch me again like that, and you'll draw back a stump.
-冷静  兄弟  -失陪
- Hold on there, little buddy. - Excuse me.
天哪  帕特里克
God. Patrick.
为什么要在这里
Why here?
我见过你看我的眼神
I've seen you looking at me.
我注意到过...
I've noticed...
你那...
your...
惹火的身材
hot body.
别害羞
Don't be shy.
你无法想象我为这一刻等了多久
You can't imagine how long I've wanted this,
从那次在亚利桑那206餐厅的圣诞派对开始
ever since that Christmas party at Arizona 206.
你知道的
You know the one.
当时你打着阿玛尼红色旋涡纹领带
You were wearing that red-striped paisley Armani tie.
我想要你
I want you.
我也想要你
I want you, too.
-帕特里克  -什么事
- Patrick! - What is it?
你去哪
Where are you going?
我要去还录像带
I've gotta return some videotapes.
帕特里克
Patrick!
周一  20号
Okay, Monday? The 20th.
周一  那...
Monday? That's...
-没有保罗·艾伦的预约  -预约...没有
- Any Paul Allen?  -Reservation... no.
-没有预约  但  -坎鲍尔
- No reservation, but... - Kimball.
我一直想找你聊聊  来我办公室
I've been wanting to talk with you. Come into my office.
琴  今天的外套很好看  松田家的吗
Jean, great jacket. Matsuda?
你记得保罗失踪那晚你在哪吗
Do you remember where you were the night of Paul's disappearance?
12月20号
Which was on the 20th of December?
天哪
God.
我大概去还录像带了吧
I guess I was probably returning videotapes.
我在跟一个叫维罗妮卡的女孩约会
I had a date with a girl named Veronica.
我得到的消息可并非如此
That's not what I've got.
什么
What?
我收到的消息不是这么说的
That's not the information I've received.
我...等等
Well, I-- Wait.
你收到了什么消息
What information have you received?
我看看
Let me see.
-你当时和...  -我可能记错了
- You were with... - Well, I could be wrong.
你最后一次跟保罗·艾伦在一起是什么时候
When was the last time you were with Paul Allen?
我们一起去看了新音乐剧
We'd gone to a new musical called
《啊! 非洲!  勇敢的非洲》
Oh, Africa, Brave Africa.
很搞笑的剧
It was a laugh riot.
大概就这样
That was about it.
我们应该是在欧瑟餐厅吃了晚饭
I think we had dinner at Orso's.
不对  是湃朵餐厅  不  是欧瑟
No, Petal... No, Orso's.
希望这些能帮到你  今天事情太多  有点分心
I hope I've been informative. Long day. Bit scattered.
我现在也有点筋疲力尽
I'm a little spent now, too.
但是...
But...
要不一周后我们约个午饭
how about lunch in a week or so?
等我理清所有的信息
When I've sorted out all this information.
好  棒极了  我很乐意
Great. Yes, I'd like that.
如果你能确定保罗·艾伦失踪那晚
And if you could try and pin down where you were
你人在哪里的话
the night of Paul Allen's disappearance,
我的工作就好做多了
it would make my job a lot easier.
当然  这件事上我支持你
Absolutely. I'm with you on that one.
休易·路易斯和新闻乐队
Huey Lewis And The News.
这张专辑挺不错
Great stuff.
我在来的路上买的  你听过吗
I just bought it on my way here. You heard it?
没有
Never.
我不太喜欢歌手
I mean, I don't really like singers.
你不是乐迷  是吧
Not a big music fan, huh?
不  我喜欢音乐
No, I like music.
只是他们...
Just, they're...
休易在我听来  曲风太像黑人了
Huey's too black-sounding for me.
萝卜青菜  各有所爱
To each his own.
那么...
So...
下周一起吃午餐吗
Lunch next week?
我会去的
I'll be there.
复活节前你会给我打电话吗
Will you call me before Easter?
可能吧
Maybe.
你今晚要做什么
What are you doing tonight?
在河畔咖啡厅吃晚餐
Dinner at River Café.
或许之后会去酒吧
Au Bar afterwards, maybe.
真好
That's nice.
我不知道你还抽烟
I never knew you smoked.
你从未注意过
You never noticed.
听着
Listen,
帕特里克
Patrick...
我们能谈谈吗
can we talk?
你看着
You look
美极了
marvelous.
没什么好说的
There's nothin' to say.
你会嫁给路易斯
You're gonna marry Luis.
可不就是很特别吗
Isn't that special.
帕特里克
Patrick...
怎么了  柯特妮
Yes, Courtney?
我要是在复活节前没见到你
If I don't see you before Easter,
祝你复活节快乐  好吗
have a nice one, okay?
你也是
You, too.
帕特里克
Patrick?
怎么了
Yeah?
没事
Nothing.
目前有理论认为
There's this theory now,
听着  目前有理论认为
listen to it, there's this theory now
你如果能通过做爱
that if you can catch the AIDS virus
感染上艾滋病  那任何病毒你都能感染
through having sex with someone, then you can catch anything.
阿兹海默症  肌肉萎缩症
Alzheimer's, muscular dystrophy,
血友病  白血病  糖尿病  阅读障碍
hemophilia, leukemia, diabetes, dyslexia.
我不确定  但我不觉得阅读障碍算是病毒
I'm not sure, but I don't think dyslexia's a virus.
谁知道呢  他们都不知道
Who knows? They don't know that.
证明看看
Prove it.
-我的天  -怎么了
- Oh, God! - What?
这玩意毒品含量少得可怜
There's a fucking milligram of sweetener.
我想吸到嗨  贝特曼
I wanna get high off this, Bateman,
而不是拿来撒在麦片上
not sprinkle it on my fucking oatmeal.
纯度确实低  不过我觉得
It's definitely weak, but I have a feeling
只要多吸点  能嗨起来的
if we do enough of it, we'll be okay.
你们能小声点吗  我在吸毒呢
Can you keep it down? I'm trying to do drugs.
去你的
Fuck you!
冷静点  快吸吧
Calm down. Do it anyway.
没错
That's right.
只要隔间的基佬觉得没关系就行了
That is, if the fag in the next stall thinks it's okay!
-去你的  -去你的
- Fuck you! - Hey. Fuck you!
抱歉  兄弟  头脑一热
Sorry, dude. Steroids.
好了  吸吧
Okay, let's do it.
克雷格去哪里了
Where did Craig go?
戈尔巴乔夫在楼下
Well, Gorbachev is downstairs.
麦克德莫特去签署
McDermott went to sign a peace treaty
美国和俄罗斯之间的和平条约
between the United States and Russia.
他推动了公开性改革
He's the one behind glasnost, you know.
"公开性"指戈尔巴乔夫在苏联倡导的
允许公开讨论国家政治的政策
他说他在一家并购公司
He said he was in mergers and acquisitions.
你还没迷糊  是吧
You're not confused, are you?
没有
No, not really.
戈尔巴乔夫不在楼下
Gorbachev is not downstairs.
凯伦说得对  戈尔巴乔夫不在楼下
Karen's right. Gorbachev's not downstairs.
他在隧道夜店里呢
He's at Tunnel.
问我一个问题
Ask me a question.
你是做什么的
So, what do you do?
我主要做
I'm into
杀人灭口
murders and executions, mostly.
你喜欢吗
Do you like it?
看情况
Well, it depends.
怎么了
Why?
我认识的大部分在并购公司的家伙
Well, most guys I know who work in mergers and acquisitions
并不喜欢这份工作
really don't like it.
那么...
So...
你在哪里健身
where do you work out?
你觉得我很蠢  对吧
You think I'm dumb, don't you?
什么
What?
你觉得我很蠢  你觉得所有模特都蠢
You think I'm dumb. You think all models are dumb.
不
No.
我真没这么想
I really don't.
没关系  我不介意
That's okay. I don't mind.
你挺可爱的
There's something sweet about you.
在玩填字游戏吗
Doin' the crossword?
骨和肉
需要帮忙吗
You need any help?
琴
Jean?
怎么了  帕特里克
Yes, Patrick?
你愿意陪我吃晚餐吗
Would you like to accompany me to dinner?
前提是
That is,
如果你有空的话
if you're not doing anything.
不  我没有别的安排
No. No, I don't have any plans.
那么...
Well...
真巧啊
isn't this a coincidence.
我们该去哪吃饭呢
Listen, where should we go?
你说了算
Anywhere you want.
别管我的想法
Let's not think about what I want.
不如说说你想去哪
How about anywhere you want?
我不知道  帕特里克  我做不了主
I don't know, Patrick. I can't make this decision.
说吧
Come on.
你想去哪里
Where do you want to go?
任何地方都行
Anywhere you want.
尽管说  我都能办到
Just say it. I can get us in anywhere.
那就去...
What about...
多西亚餐厅怎么样
Dorsia?
所以
So.
琴想去多西亚餐厅
Dorsia is where Jean wants to go.
我不知道
I don't know.
不  都听你的
No, we'll go wherever you want to go.
多西亚餐厅不错
Dorsia is fine.
您好  这里是多西亚餐厅
Dorsia. Yes?
麻烦预定两个座位  今晚九点
Yeah, can you take two tonight at, let's say, 9:00?
我们订满了
We're totally booked.
真的吗  太好了
Really? That's great.
不  我是说我们订满了
No, I said we are totally booked.
晚上九点两个座位  完美
Two at 9:00? Perfect.
晚上见
See you then.
怎么了
Yeah?
你...
You're...
穿得挺美
dressed okay.
你没有留名字
You didn't give a name.
他们认识我
They know me.
你不如来我家找我吧
Why don't you meet me at my place?
晚上七点  先喝一杯
At 7:00. For drinks.
琴
And, Jean?
我们出门前得换身衣服
We'll want to change before we go out.
帕特里克  太漂亮了
Patrick, it's so elegant.
视野真好
What a wonderful view.
琴
Jean.
吃冰沙吗
Sorbet?
谢谢  帕特里克  我想吃
Thanks, Patrick. I'd love some.
你要吃一口吗
Do you want a bite?
我在节食  但还是谢谢你
I'm on a diet. But thank you.
你不需要减肥
You don't need to lose any weight.
你在开玩笑  对吗
You're kidding, right?
你看起来很棒  非常健康
You look great. Very fit.
再瘦点  再帅点  总归是好的
You can always be thinner, look better.
或许我们不该去吃晚餐
Well, maybe we shouldn't go out to dinner.
我不想动摇你的意志力
I don't want to ruin your willpower.
不  没关系
No, it's all right.
反正我意志力也不强
I'm not very good at controlling it anyway.
那么...
So, listen...
你想要什么样的生活
What do you really want to do with your life?
简略总结就好  还有
Just briefly. Summarize. And
别告诉我你想被孩子们围着  好吗
don't tell me you enjoy working with children, okay?
这个嘛
Well,
我想去旅行
I'd like to travel and
或许还想回学校读书  但是
maybe go back to school, but
我也不太清楚
I don't really know.
我现在所处的人生阶段  看起来
I'm at a point in my life where there seems to be
有很多种可能性
so many possibilities.
但我不知道  心里没底
But I don't know. I'm just so unsure.
你有男朋友吗
Do you have a boyfriend?
没有
No, not really.
有意思
Interesting.
你在跟谁交往吗
Are you seeing anyone?
我是说认真的关系
I mean, seriously?
可能吧
Maybe.
我不知道
I don't know.
算不上
Not really.
琴
Jean?
你感到满足吗
Do you feel fulfilled?
我是说在生活上
I mean, in your life?
应该吧
I guess I do.
长时间以来  我太专注工作了
For a long time, I was too focused on my work.
但现在  我真的开始思考转变
But now I've really begun to think about changing myself.
自我发展和成长
You know, developing and growing.
成长
Growing.
很高兴听到你这么说
I'm glad you said that.
你知道
Did you know that
泰德·邦迪的第一只狗是牧羊犬
Ted Bundy's first dog, a collie,
美国七十年代连环杀手
叫做蕾西[姑娘]
was named Lassie?
你听说过吗
Had you heard this?
泰德·邦迪是谁
Who's Ted Bundy?
算了
Forget it.
那是什么
What's that?
强力胶带
Duct tape.
我拿来...
I need it for...
封点东西
taping something.
帕特里克
Patrick?
你曾经想过
Have you ever wanted to
让某人幸福吗
make someone happy?
什么  不  把勺子放进纸杯里
What? No! Put it in the carton!
抱歉
Sorry.
琴
Jean?
你说什么
What?
让某人幸福
Make someone happy.
你曾经这么想过吗
Have you ever wanted to?
我在找...
I'm looking for...
我觉得可以说是
I guess you could say
我只是想和一个特别的人
I just want to have a meaningful relationship
拥有一段有意义的关系
with someone special.
帕特里克  帕特里克
Patrick. Patrick.
我知道你在家
I know you're there.
快接电话  坏男人
Pick up the phone, you bad boy.
你今晚要做什么
What are you up to tonight?
是我  别想躲着我
It's me. Don't try to hide.
希望你现在
I hope you're not out there
不是在跟哪个小妞鬼混
with some little number you picked up,
因为你是我的  贝特曼先生
because you're mine, Mr. Bateman.
我的邻家男孩
My boy next door.
不过你从不给我打电话  虽然你答应过
Anyway you never called me, and you said you would.
我会给琴留言来提醒你
And I'll leave a message for Jean about this, too, to remind you,
不过我们要跟梅拉尼娅和泰勒共进晚餐
but we're having dinner with Melania and Taylor.
你认识梅拉尼娅  她去过野玫瑰餐厅
You know Melania. She went to Sweet Briar.
我们在康奈尔俱乐部碰面
and we're meeting at the Cornell Club,
所以我明早再给你打电话  亲爱的
so I'll call you tomorrow morning, honey.
抱歉  我知道你讨厌这个称呼
Sorry. I know you hate that.
再见  帕特里克
Bye, Patrick.
再见  霸道总裁先生
Bye, Mr. Big Time CEO.
再见
Bye-bye.
那是伊芙琳吗
Was that Evelyn?
你还在跟她交往吗
Are you still seeing her?
抱歉  我无权过问
I'm sorry. I have no right to ask that.
你想让我走吗
Do you want me to go?
对
Yeah.
我觉得我控制不了自己
I don't think I can control myself.
我知道我该离开了
I know I should go.
我知道我总是和名草有主的男人纠缠不清
I know I have a tendency to get involved with unavailable men.
我是说
I mean...
你希望我离开吗
Do you want me to go?
我觉得如果你留下
I think if you stay,
就会有坏事发生
something bad will happen.
我觉得我可能会伤害你
I think I might hurt you.
你不想受伤  对吧
You don't want to get hurt, do you?
是  我不想
No. No, I guess not.
我不想弄得一身淤青
I don't want to get bruised.
你说得对
You're right.
我该走了
I should go.
别忘了你明天约了唐纳德·坎鲍尔
Don't forget you have a lunch date tomorrow
在史密斯和沃尔伦斯基餐厅吃午餐
with Donald Kimball at Smith and Wollensky's.
多谢
Thanks.
我完全忘了这事
It slipped my mind completely.
话说
So.
他失踪的那晚
The night he disappeared.
你想起来自己干什么了吗
Any new thoughts about what you did?
我不确定
Not sure.
我洗了个澡
I had a shower,
吃了点冰沙
and some sorbet.
我想你是把各种约会搞混了
I think you're getting your dates mixed up.
怎么搞混了
But how?
那你觉得保罗那晚去哪里了
Where do you place Paul that night?
从他的日程表来看
According to his datebook,
他的秘书也证实过了
and this was verified by his secretary,
那晚他和马库斯·哈博斯特拉姆吃了晚餐
he had dinner with Marcus Halberstram.
-然后呢  -我问了他
- And? - I questioned him.
-马库斯吗  -是的  他否认了
- Marcus? - Yes, and he denies it.
尽管一开始他不是很确定
Though, at first, he couldn't be sure.
-但他否认了  -没错
- But he denied it. - Yes.
马库斯有不在场证明吗
Well, does Marcus have an alibi?
有
Yes.
他有吗  你确定
He does? You're sure?
我检查过了  清白无误
I've checked it out. It's clean.
现在的问题是
Now...
你当时在哪
where were you?
马库斯在哪
Where was Marcus?
他没和保罗·艾伦在一起
He wasn't with Paul Allen.
那他和谁在一起
Who was he with?
他当时在亚特兰蒂斯餐厅
He was at Atlantis
在场的有克雷格·麦克德莫特
with Craig McDermott,
弗雷德里克·迪博
Frederick Dibble,
哈利·纽曼  乔治·布特纳  还有...
Harry Newman, George Butner, and...
你
you.
是的  没错  当然了
Right, yeah. Of course.
我们之前希望保罗·艾伦能来
We had wanted Paul Allen to come,
但他另有安排了
but he had made plans,
我猜我是在隔天晚上和维多利亚吃的晚餐
and I guess I had dinner with Victoria the following night.
在我看来  我觉得那家伙有点疯了
Personally, I think the guy went a little nutso.
才暂时离开这里一阵  可能他是去了伦敦
Split town for a while. Maybe he did go to London,
观光  喝酒什么的
sightseeing, drinking, whatever.
总之  我确定他迟早会露面的
Anyway, I'm pretty sure he'll turn up sooner or later.
我是说  怀疑他的某个朋友
I mean, to think that one of his friends killed him
无缘无故杀了他什么的  也太荒谬了
for no reason whatsoever would be too ridiculous.
不是吗  帕特里克
Isn't that right, Patrick?
克里斯蒂  克里斯蒂
Christie, Christie.
我不太确定要不要来
I'm not so sure about this.
上次做完之后  我不得不去了急诊室
I had to go to emergency after last time.
这次不会像上次那样了
This won't be anything like last time.
-我保证  -我不觉得
- I promise. - I don't think so.
就上车跟我说会儿话
Just come in the limo and talk to me for a minute.
司机在这  你很安全
Driver's here. You're safe.
绝对跟上次不一样  我保证
Nothing like last time. I promise.
好吧
All right.
你看起来挺好的
So you're looking great.
你最近怎么样
How've you been?
上次完事后我其实得动个小手术
Well, I actually might need a little surgery after last time.
真的吗
Really?
我朋友跟我说我可能还得请个律师
My friend told me I should maybe even get a lawyer.
律师们都很复杂
Lawyers are so complicated.
别那么做
Don't do that.
拿上支票吧
Here's a check.
现在付一半  完事付一半
Half now, half later.
好吧
Okay.
你叫克里斯蒂
Your name's Christie.
我们要去见我一个朋友  伊丽莎白
We're meeting a friend of mine, Elizabeth.
她马上要来我的新公寓  和我们一起
She'll be joining us in my new apartment shortly.
你会喜欢她的
You'll like her.
她是个不错的姑娘
She's a very nice girl.
你看上去很面熟
You look really familiar.
你去过多尔顿吗
Did you go to Dalton?
我觉得我在冲浪酒吧见过你  是吧
I think I met you at the Surf Bar, didn't I?
和斯派西一起
With Spicey?
可能不是和斯派西一起  但肯定是在冲浪酒吧
Well, maybe not with Spicey, but definitely at Surf Bar.
你知道的吧  冲浪酒吧
You know, Surf Bar?
总之  冲浪酒吧现在很差劲  太糟糕了
Anyway, Surf Bar sucks now. It's terrible.
我去那里参加过马尔科姆·福布斯的生日派对
Went to a birthday party there for Malcolm Forbes.
天哪  糟糕透顶
Oh, my God, please.
这里比你另外那间公寓要好
This is nicer than your other apartment.
也没那么好吧
Well, it's not that nice.
你们是在哪认识的
Where did you two meet?
天哪  我们相识于...
Oh, God. We met at...
85年还是86年  肯塔基州的德比马赛
Oh, God, at the Kentucky Derby in '85 or '86.
你当时和那个荡妇爱丽森·普尔在一起
You were hanging out with that bimbo Allison Poole.
性感尤物
Hot number.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
她是个性感尤物
She was a hot number.
有张铂金卡  她就愿意给你口一发
Get a platinum card, she'd give you a blow job.
这女孩在美黑沙龙工作
Listen, this girl worked at a tanning salon.
还需要我多说吗
Need I say more?
你是做什么的
What do you do?
她是我的...
She's my...
表妹
Cousin.
她来自...
She's from...
法国
France.
你的电话呢  我得给哈利打个电话
Where's your phone? I've gotta call Harley.
你在哪里过夏天  南安普敦吗
Where do you summer? Southampton?
不
No.
老天  转到他的答录机了
Oh, God. It's his machine.
伊丽莎白  现在是凌晨三点
Elizabeth, it's 3:00 in the morning.
他是个毒贩  现在是他的客流高峰期
He's a goddamn drug dealer. These are his peak hours.
-别告诉他你在这里  -我为什么要说
- Don't tell him you're here. - Why would I?
这酒味道好奇怪
This tastes weird.
哈利  是我  我需要你的服务
Harley, it's me. I need your services.
想怎么理解都行
Translate that however you want.
我在...
I'm at...
-你在保罗·艾伦家  -谁
- You're at Paul Allen's. - Who?
-保罗·艾伦  -我要的是号码  蠢货
- Paul Allen. - I want the number, idiot.
反正我现在在保罗·诺曼家  晚点再打给你
Anyway, I'm at Paul Norman's, and I'll try you again later.
如果明晚我没在运河酒吧看到你
If I don't see you at Canal Bar tomorrow night,
我就要派我的发型师去找你了
I'm gonna sic my hair dresser on you.
你认识那个失踪的人吗
Did you know that guy who disappeared?
他不是在皮尔斯&皮尔斯公司上班吗
Didn't he work at Pierce & Pierce?
他是你朋友吗
Was he a friend of yours?
不是
No.
你有可卡因吗
Do you have any coke?
或者酣乐欣[安眠药]  我要来一片
Or Halcion? I would take a Halcion.
听着
Listen.
我只想看到
I would just like to see
你们俩
the two of you
开搞
get it on.
有什么不好吗
What's wrong with that?
完全无病
It's totally disease-free.
帕特里克  你这个疯子
Patrick, you're a lunatic.
得了
Come on.
你不觉得克里斯蒂很有魅力吗
Don't you find Christie attractive?
别这么不正经
Let's not get lewd.
我现在没心情说不正经的事
I'm in no mood for a lewd conversation.
来吧
Come on.
我觉得这会让你性奋的
I think it'd be a turn-on.
他一直这样吗
Does he do this all the time?
克里斯蒂  你没喝你的酒
Christie, you're not drinking your wine.
你是说你从来没跟女孩搞过吗
You're telling me you've never gotten it on with a girl?
没有
No.
我不是同性恋
I'm not a lesbian.
你为什么会觉得我会对那个感兴趣
Why would you think I would be into that?
因为比如说  你去了莎拉·劳伦斯学院
Well, you went to Sarah Lawrence, for one thing.
在那里上学的男生才是同性恋  帕特里克
Those are Sarah Lawrence guys, Patrick.
你让我感觉好奇怪
You're making me feel weird.
你知道
Did you know
惠特妮·休斯顿首张黑胶大碟
that Whitney Houston's debut LP,
美国女歌手
就叫《惠特妮·休斯顿》
called simply Whitney Houston,
里面还有四首冠军单曲吗
had four number-one singles on it?
你知道这个吗  克里斯蒂
Did you know that, Christie?
你真的听惠特妮·休斯顿吗
You actually listen to Whitney Houston?
你有惠特妮·休斯顿的唱片吗
You own a Whitney Houston CD?
还不止一张吗
More than one?
很难从那么多好歌里选出最爱的一首
It's hard to choose a favorite among so many great tracks.
但《最伟大的爱》
But "The Greatest Love Of All"
是所有描写人类自我保护和尊严的歌曲中
is one of the best, most powerful songs ever written
最精彩  最有力的一首
about self-preservation, dignity.
其亘古不变的寓意跨越一切界限
Its universal message crosses all boundaries
用希望滋润人们的心田
and instills one with the hope
告诉他们提升自我  永远不会太迟
that it's not too late to better ourselves.
因为  伊丽莎白
Since, Elizabeth,
在我们所处的这个世界中
it's impossible, in this world we live in,
我们不可能与他人感同身受
to empathize with others,
但我们可以顾影自怜
we can always empathize with ourselves.
这是很重要的寓意
It's an important message.
很关键
Crucial, really.
这张专辑对这一点进行了优美的诠释
And it's beautifully stated on the album.
雅皮士荡妇
不许踢脸  你个贱人
Not the face, you bitch!
别他妈踢脸  你这个垃圾
Not the fuckin' face, you piece of bitch trash!
我想要一个可靠的承诺
I want a firm commitment.
我觉得  伊芙琳
I think, Evelyn,
我们已经失去联系了
that we've lost touch.
为什么  怎么了
Why? What's wrong?
我无法修正自己
My need to engage in homicidal behavior
嗜杀成性的行为
on a massive scale cannot be corrected,
但我没别的方法来满足自己的需要了
but I have no other way to fulfill my needs.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
谈什么  帕特里克
Talk about what, Patrick?
结束了  伊芙琳
It's over, Evelyn.
都结束了
It's all over.
别生气嘛
Touchy, touchy.
抱歉我提起婚礼的事
I'm sorry I brought up the wedding.
我们不说就是了  好吗
Let's just avoid the issue, all right?
我们去喝咖啡吧
Now, are we having coffee?
我他妈很认真  我们已经结束了
I'm fucking serious. It's fucking over. Us.
这不是玩笑
This is no joke.
我觉得我们还是别再见面了
I don't think we should see each other anymore.
但我们有共同的朋友
But your friends are my friends, and my friends are your friends.
我不觉得这能行得通
I really don't think it would work.
你这里有东西
You have a little something--
我知道我们有共同的朋友
I know that your friends are my friends,
我想过这事了
and I've thought about that.
他们就当你的朋友好了
You can have them.
你是认真的  对吧
You're really serious, aren't you?
是的
Yes, I am.
那过去呢
What about the past?
-我们的过去呢  -我们从来没有共同的过去
- Our past? - We never really shared one.
-你简直不近人情  -不  我尚存人性
- You're inhuman. - No, I'm in touch with humanity.
伊芙琳  我很抱歉
Evelyn, I'm sorry.
我只是
I just...
你对我来说没那么重要
You're not terribly important to me.
不
Oh, no.
不  不要
No, no.
我知道我有时候行为古怪
I know my behavior can be erratic sometimes.
你想让我怎么样
What do you want me to do?
你到底想要什么
What is it that you want?
如果你真的想为我做点什么
If you really want to do something for me,
就别在这里丢人了
then stop making this scene right now.
-天哪  我不敢相信  -我要走了
- Oh, God, I can't believe this. - l'm leaving.
我评估了一下形势  我要走了
I've assessed the situation, and I'm going.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
离开这里就行
Just leaving.
但是去哪里呢
But where?
我得去还录像带
I have to return some videotapes.
取现
你好啊  小猫咪
Here, kitty, kitty.
喂我一只流浪猫
天哪  你在干什么
Oh, my God. What are you doing?
住手
Stop that.
放下武器  快点
Drop the weapon! Drop it now!
趴在地上  把...
Get on the ground! Put--
要熬夜加班吗  史密斯先生
Burning the midnight oil, Mr. Smith?
别忘了登记
Hey, now don't forget to sign in.
哈罗德  我是贝特曼  帕特里克·贝特曼
Harold, it's Bateman, Patrick Bateman.
你是我的律师  所以我觉得应该告诉你
You're my lawyer, so I think you should know
我杀了很多人
I've killed a lot of people.
在上城区的公寓杀了几个应召女郎
Some escort girls in the apartment uptown,
杀过几个流浪汉  可能五到十个
some homeless people, maybe five or ten,
还杀了在中央公园碰到的一个纽约大学女孩
an NYU girl I met in Central Park.
我把她丢在某家甜甜圈店后面的停车场了
I left her in a parking lot behind some doughnut shop.
我用钉枪杀了贝森妮  我的前女友
I killed Bethany, my old girlfriend, with a nail gun,
还有个家伙
and some man,
某个带着条狗的基佬
some faggot with a dog.
上周  我又用电锯
Last week, I killed another girl
杀了一个女孩
with a chain saw.
我必须这么做
I had to.
她差点就跑了
She almost got away,
还有...
and...
还有别的什么人  我记不清了
Someone else there. I can't remember.
可能是个模特
Maybe a model.
她也死了
She's dead, too,
还有保罗·艾伦
and Paul Allen.
我照着保罗·艾伦的脸来了一斧子  把他杀了
I killed Paul Allen with an ax in the face.
他的尸体正在地狱厨房的一个浴缸里溶解
His body is dissolving in a bathtub in Hell's Kitchen.
纽约克林顿区俗称  早年间为曼哈顿著名贫民窟
我不想遗漏什么
I don't want to leave anything out here.
我大概杀了20个人
I guess I've killed maybe 20 people,
或者40个人
maybe 40.
我用录像带记录了很多
I have tapes of a lot of it.
有些女孩看过那些录像带
Some of the girls have seen the tapes.
我甚至...
I even...
我吃了其中几个人的脑子
I ate some of their brains...
我试着用他们来做菜
and I tried to cook a little.
今晚我...
Tonight I...
我不得不杀了很多人
I just had to kill a lot of people,
而且...
and...
我不确定
I'm not sure
这次我能不能逃脱
I'm gonna get away with it this time.
所以我的意思是...
So, I mean...
我猜...
I guess...
我是个非常...
I'm a pretty...
我应该是个非常变态的人
I mean, I guess I'm a pretty sick guy.
所以...
So...
如果你明天回来
if you get back tomorrow,
我可能会去哈利酒吧
I may show up at Harry's Bar.
所以你懂的
So, you know.
留点神
Keep your eyes open.
你是约了两点的客人吗
Are you my 2:00?
不是
No.
有事需要效劳吗
Can I help you?
我在找...
I'm looking for...
保罗·艾伦的家
Paul Allen's place.
他不住在这里吗
Doesn't he live here?
他不住在这里
No, he doesn't.
你确定吗
You sure?
你看见《纽约时报》上的广告了吗
You saw the ad in the Times?
没有
No.
看见了  我看见了
Yeah. I mean, yeah.
就在《纽约时报》上
In the Times.
《纽约时报》上没有广告
There was no ad in the Times.
我觉得你现在该离开了
I think you should go now.
但是我...
But I think...
我想知道这里发生了什么
I want to know what happened here.
麻烦别给我添乱
Don't make any trouble, please.
你最好赶快离开
I suggest you go.
别再回来
Don't come back.
不会的
I won't.
别担心
Don't worry.
帕特里克·贝特曼的办公室
Patrick Bateman's office.
琴
Jean?
-我需要帮忙  -帕特里克  是你吗
- I need help. - Patrick, is that you?
琴  我不
Jean, I'm not--
克雷格·麦克德莫特打来过
Craig McDermott called.
他想约上你  大卫·范帕顿
Wants to meet you, David Van Patten
还有蒂姆·布莱斯一起去哈利酒吧喝酒
and Tim Bryce at Harry's for drinks.
天哪
Oh, God.
你说什么  蠢婊子
What did you say, you dumb bitch?
帕特里克  我听不清
Patrick, I can't hear you.
我在干什么
What am I doing?
你在哪里  帕特里克  怎么了
Where are you, Patrick? What's wrong?
琴  我觉得我今天下午
I don't think I'm gonna make it, Jean,
应该没法去办公室了
to the office this afternoon.
为什么
Why?
你拒绝他们就行了
Just say no!
怎么了  帕特里克  你还好吗
What is it, Patrick? Are you all right?
别他妈哭丧着声音说话
Stop sounding so fucking sad!
天哪
Jesus!
三人桌
Table for three.
贝特曼  你眼睛里有血丝  工作太辛苦了吗
Bateman, you look a little wild-eyed. Rough day at the office?
布莱斯回来了  他在喝矿泉水
Hey, look, Bryce is back, and he's drinking mineral water.
他已经改头换面了
He's a changed man except he
然而他还是没法订到座位来拯救他的生活
still can't get a reservation to save his life.
你不如试试伍斯特150餐厅
Why don't you just try 150 Wooster?
预约好之前  我哪里也不去
I'm not going anywhere unless we have a reservation.
马戏团餐厅  弗拉明戈之东餐厅  牡蛎酒吧
Le Cirque, Flamingo East, Oyster Bar.
快点  伙计们  我们找家餐厅
Come on, faggots, let's get a res.
把衬衫穿好
Keep your shirt on.
可能是裤子背带掉了
Maybe lose the suspenders.
要预约一下八点半
Need a reservation for 8:30.
失陪一下  先生们
Excuse me, gentlemen.
马上回来
Right back.
十点不太行
Ten would not be any good, no.
你就给他们打个电话
Just fucking call them.
-手机给我  我来打  -我再给你回电话
- Give me the phone. I'll do it. - I'll call ya back.
接受吧  日本人到了九十年代末
Face it. The Japanese will own most of this country
就会占领这国家的绝大部分
by the end of the '90s.
别胡说了  卡恩斯
Shut up, Carnes.
才不会呢
They will not.
那么  哈罗德
So, Harold,
你收到我的信息没
did you get my message?
当然收到了  太搞笑了
Jesus, yes. That was hilarious.
那就是你  对吧
That was you, wasn't it?
当然是我
Yeah, naturally.
贝特曼杀了艾伦和应召女郎
Bateman killing Allen and the escort girls.
真是让人难以置信  太厉害了
That's fabulous. That's rich.
你这话什么意思
What exactly do you mean?
你留的信息啊
The message you left.
对了  戴维斯  辛西娅怎么样
By the way, Davis, how's Cynthia?
你们还在一起  对吧
You're still seeing her, right?
等等  哈罗德  你什么意思
Wait, Harold. What do you mean?
抱歉  没什么意思
Excuse me. Nothing.
见到你很开心
It's good to see you.
那个是爱德华·塔沃斯吗
Is that Edward Towers?
戴维斯
Davis.
我不是那种会说别人坏话的人
I'm not one to badmouth anyone.
你的笑话很好笑
Your joke was amusing,
但是说真的
but come on, man.
你有个致命的缺陷
You had one fatal flaw.
贝特曼就是个呆子
Bateman is such a dork.
一个无聊  懦弱且无足轻重的小角色
Such a boring, spineless lightweight.
如果你说杀人的是布莱斯或者麦克德莫特我还信
Now if you said Bryce or McDermott...
不然就真的很搞笑了
Otherwise, it was amusing.
失陪一下  我真的要走了
Now if you'll excuse me, I really must be going.
等等
Wait.
别说了
Stop.
是我干的  卡恩斯
I did it, Carnes.
我杀了他
I killed him.
我是帕特里克·贝特曼
I'm Patrick Bateman.
我他妈把艾伦的头砍了下来
I chopped Allen's fucking head off.
我给你留的全部信息都是真的
The whole message I left on your machine was true.
抱歉
Excuse me.
我真的该走了
I really must be going now.
不  听着
No, listen.
你不知道我是谁吗
Don't you know who I am?
我不是戴维斯
I'm not Davis.
我是帕特里克·贝特曼
I'm Patrick Bateman.
我们一直在电话上联系
We talk on the phone all the time.
你认不出我吗
Don't you recognize me?
你是我的律师
You're my lawyer.
现在  卡恩斯
Now, Carnes...
听我说
listen.
你仔仔细细听好了
Listen very, very carefully.
我杀了保罗·艾伦
I killed Paul Allen...
而且我很喜欢这种感觉
and I liked it.
我没办法解释得更清楚了
I can't make myself any clearer.
但那绝对不可能
But that's simply not possible.
我现在也不觉得这样很搞笑了
And I don't find this funny anymore.
这从来就不是个笑话
It never was supposed to be.
-为什么不可能  -就是不可能
- Why isn't it possible? - lt's just not.
为什么  你个蠢货
Why not, you stupid bastard?
因为我和保罗·艾伦在伦敦吃了两次饭
Because I had dinner with Paul Allen twice in London,
-就在十天前  -不  你...
- just ten days ago. - No, you...
没有
didn't.
现在  抱歉失陪了
Now, if you'll excuse me.
我们已经见识过不信任会带来的后果
We've seen the results of that mistrust
诸如谎言  分歧  错误等
in the form of lies, divisions, and mistakes.
我们需要找到方法来合作
We need to find a way to cooperate
同时也要认识到对外政策
while realizing foreign policy
不能由委员会来执行
can't be run by committee.
我相信现在大家应该越来越意识到
And I believe there's now the growing sense
通过合作我们能收获更多成功
that we can accomplish more by cooperating.
而且最终
And, in the end,
这或许是在伊朗门事件的混乱中
this may be the eventual blessing in disguise
伊朗门事件即美国向伊朗秘密出售武器一事被揭露
从而造成里根政府严重政治危机的事件
最后的因祸得福
to come out of the Iran-Contra mess.
他怎么能说这种谎
How can he lie like that?
-他怎么能扯这种谎  -什么谎
- How can he pull that shit? - What shit?
我们到底在哪里预定了位置
Now where do we have reservations at?
我不是真的很饿
I mean, I'm not really hungry,
但我还是想在某家餐厅预定位置
but I'd like to have reservations someplace.
你怎么能这么...
How can you be so fucking...
我也不知道
I don't know...
对这事这么淡定
cool about it?
可能有些人天生就淡定
Some guys are just born cool, I guess.
贝特曼
Bateman.
你傻乐什么呢
What are you so fucking zany about?
我就是个快乐的人
I'm just a happy camper.
嗨起来
Rockin' and a-rollin'!
兄弟  你看
Oh, brother! Look,
他表现得像个人畜无害的小老头  但是
he presents himself as this harmless old codger, but
内在
inside...
但是内在...
But inside...
但是内在根本无关紧要
But inside doesn't matter.
内在  什么内在
Inside? Yes? Inside?
信不信由你  布莱斯  我们一直在听你说
Believe it or not, Bryce, we're actually listening to you.
得了  贝特曼
Come on, Bateman,
你觉得呢
what do you think?
无所谓
Whatever.
是谁这么蠢  点了干啤
Whose moronic idea was it to order dry beers?
我要威士忌
I need a scotch.
再也没有障碍了
There are no more barriers to cross.
我有的一切失控  疯癫
All I have in common with the uncontrollable and the insane,
恶毒  邪恶
the vicious and the evil,
我造成的所有混乱  以及我对它的完全冷漠
all the mayhem I have caused and my utter indifference toward it,
如今我都超越了
I have now surpassed.
我的痛苦持续而尖锐
My pain is constant and sharp,
我也不为任何人祈祷世界更美好
and I do not hope for a better world for anyone.
说实话  我希望其他人尝尝我的痛苦
In fact, I want my pain to be inflicted on others.
我希望谁都逃不掉
I want no one to escape.
但即便承认了这些
But even after admitting this,
我也并没有一种宣泄后的快感
there is no catharsis.
我依然无法受到惩罚
My punishment continues to elude me,
我也没有更加了解自己
and I gain no deeper knowledge of myself.
我所说的话都只是老调重弹
No new knowledge can be extracted from my telling.
这种忏悔毫无意义
This confession has meant nothing.